https://www.skillsusa.org/privacy-policy/

MENUMENUAbout
Helping Students Excel
Overview of SkillsUSAWhy Career and Technical Education?SkillsUSA FrameworkSuccess Stories
National Organization
Headquarters OfficeBoard of DirectorsOfficial National PartnersNational OfficersHistory and Brand ResourcesValues and VisionAnnual ReportThemeCareers at SkillsUSAContact
State and Local Chapters
Start a ChapterState Association DirectorsDues, Deadlines and Conference DatesChapter Leaders
Membership Resources
Join
Join, Register or LoginMembership KitMembership FAQMembership ReportCollege Campus Affiliation PlanTotal Participation Plan (HS and MS)AlumniLeadership Opportunities
Resources
AdvisorsStudentsChaptersState DirectorsAlumni and Friends AssociationProgram of WorkEducational Resources CatalogSkillsUSA Branded MerchandiseSkillsUSA CONNECT
Scholarships, Grants and Awards
Scholarships and Financial AidGrantsAwards
Competitions
Competitions
SkillsUSA ChampionshipsWorldSkills CompetitionNLSC Pin and T-shirt Design ChallengePhoto ContestCareerSafe Video ContestState and Local Competitions2020 SkillsUSA Week T-shirt Design Contest
Events
Events
National Leadership and Skills ConferenceSkillsUSA TECHSPO Trade ShowSkillsUSA WeekNational Week of ServiceSkillsUSA National Signing DayState and Local Events
Training
WebinarsTraining Resource LibraryState Officer, Chapter Leader and Advisor TrainingWashington Leadership Training Institute (WLTI)
Programs
By Grade Level
Middle SchoolHigh SchoolCollege/Postsecondary
Programs and Assessments
Program of WorkSkillsUSA Career EssentialsChapter Excellence ProgramJump Into STEM!CareerSafe Online Safety TrainingMentoring: Student2StudentCareer ClustersGeneration T
News
Publications and News
Press RoomActive Advisor NewsAlumni NewsletterChapter NewsPodcastsSkillsUSA Champions Magazine
Get Involved
Get Involved
JoinAlumniParentsAdvertise, Exhibit and SupportBe An Advocate/Advocacy SiteDonateVolunteer
Search
MENUMENUAbout
Helping Students Excel
Overview of SkillsUSAWhy Career and Technical Education?SkillsUSA FrameworkSuccess Stories
National Organization
Headquarters OfficeBoard of DirectorsOfficial National PartnersNational OfficersHistory and Brand ResourcesValues and VisionAnnual ReportThemeCareers at SkillsUSAContact
State and Local Chapters
Start a ChapterState Association DirectorsDues, Deadlines and Conference DatesChapter Leaders
Membership Resources
Join
Join, Register or LoginMembership KitMembership FAQMembership ReportCollege Campus Affiliation PlanTotal Participation Plan (HS and MS)AlumniLeadership Opportunities
Resources
AdvisorsStudentsChaptersState DirectorsAlumni and Friends AssociationProgram of WorkEducational Resources CatalogSkillsUSA Branded MerchandiseSkillsUSA CONNECT
Scholarships, Grants and Awards
Scholarships and Financial AidGrantsAwards
Competitions
Competitions
SkillsUSA ChampionshipsWorldSkills CompetitionNLSC Pin and T-shirt Design ChallengePhoto ContestCareerSafe Video ContestState and Local Competitions2020 SkillsUSA Week T-shirt Design Contest
Events
Events
National Leadership and Skills ConferenceSkillsUSA TECHSPO Trade ShowSkillsUSA WeekNational Week of ServiceSkillsUSA National Signing DayState and Local Events
Training
WebinarsTraining Resource LibraryState Officer, Chapter Leader and Advisor TrainingWashington Leadership Training Institute (WLTI)
Programs
By Grade Level
Middle SchoolHigh SchoolCollege/Postsecondary
Programs and Assessments
Program of WorkSkillsUSA Career EssentialsChapter Excellence ProgramJump Into STEM!CareerSafe Online Safety TrainingMentoring: Student2StudentCareer ClustersGeneration T
News
Publications and News
Press RoomActive Advisor NewsAlumni NewsletterChapter NewsPodcastsSkillsUSA Champions Magazine
Get Involved
Get Involved
JoinAlumniParentsAdvertise, Exhibit and SupportBe An Advocate/Advocacy SiteDonateVolunteer
Search
Privacy Policy
SkillsUSA.org > Privacy Policy
This website is owned and operated by SkillsUSA. We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us and how we treat that information. SkillsUSA is committed to honoring our members’ privacy preferences.
This policy covers www.skillsusa.org, www.skillsusa-register.org, www.CareerEssentials.org, WorldSkillsUSA.org, SkillsUSAConnect.org and SkillsUSAChampions.org which are owned and operated by SkillsUSA Inc. We encourage you to take the time to read this privacy policy and those of any website you visit.
Information Collected
Purchases and Registration
To purchase items and register for events on this website you must create an account and provide at minimum your name, address, phone number and email address. For information about the handling of your credit card information, please see the section below titled “Security of Your Information.”
Subscribing to e-News Alerts and Active Advisor News
To sign up for alerts and e-newsletters, you are in most cases only required to provide us with your full name and email address.
We’ve enabled some Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising (e.g., Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting).
Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings at Google.
Use of Information
Your information will be used to issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments, and to send information to you about SkillsUSA and our services. You may opt-out of mailings at any time if you do not wish to receive non-business critical information from us. SkillsUSA will not sell your email address for commercial purposes.
Photography
By providing an image to SkillsUSA Inc., Leesburg, Va., you are granting SkillsUSA the rights to using this image in print, electronic, video and social media. This also includes tagging SkillsUSA in images shared on social media sites. Reproduction beyond usage by SkillsUSA Inc. is prohibited.
How to Opt-Out
E-Newsletters
If at any time you wish to stop receiving an electronic newsletter from SkillsUSA, you may opt-out by selecting the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of every message, or by contacting us at info@skillsusa.org. Please provide enough information for us to be able to identify you and comply with your request.
Security of Your Information
We will take appropriate steps to protect the security of your personal information. We will also protect your personal information in storage. We have implemented security policies, rules, and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: unauthorized access; improper use or disclosure; unauthorized modification; and unlawful destruction or accidental loss. All our employees who have access to, and are associated with processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors’ personal data.
All sensitive information (such as your credit card information) provided to SkillsUSA through our website is transmitted to our credit card processor using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. No credit card information is stored on our site.
Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can ever be 100 percent secure. While we strive to protect your information to the fullest extent, we cannot ensure or completely guarantee the security of such information.
You can also use this handy browser add-on to opt-out of Google Analytics.
Third Party Access to Information
Some third party vendors may have access to personally identifying information shared with us via this site.
VendorPurpose
AbsorbLearning Management System
MagentoE-commerce platform
PersonifyMembership Portal
Training WheelsMembership System and Conference Registration System
Smart RegCourtesy Corps Conference Registration
Marcia StricklandCoach and Hotline Operator
Katie RodebaughCoach
Lauri DomerHotline Operator
Payten GallatinCoach and Hotline Operator
James HarperHotline Operator and Conference Registration System
Chris Cronbaugh National Officer Program
DonorPerfectApplications and donations.
WufooScholarships and other applications and/or registrations.
Links to Third Party Sites
We provide links to third-party sites. Since we do not control those websites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third party sites.
Questions and Contact Information
SkillsUSA welcomes comments and questions on this policy. We are dedicated to protecting your personal information and will make every reasonable effort to keep that information secure.
If you have any questions, please contact us:
info@skillsusa.org
703-777-8810
FAX: 703-777-8999
SkillsUSA
14001 SkillsUSA Way
Leesburg, VA 20176
The information you provide to us will also be covered by this policy.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
We may change or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post an appropriate notice of changes to the Privacy Policy on our site. Privacy Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date we post the revised Privacy Policy to the Site, as well as to existing information held by us.
Last Revised: March 1, 2018
FERPA
I. Purpose
SkillsUSA Student Data Privacy Policy
The purpose of this policy is to ensure that SkillsUSA and its member organizations take appropriate steps to protect any personally identifiable information (PII) of students and related data. Although SkillsUSA is not an educational institution as defined in 34 CFR Part 99, SkillsUSA is committed to ensuring that all PII is protected and that SkillsUSA members are made aware of all rights and responsibilities regarding protecting PII.
II. Information Collected
Throughout the various platforms and databases that SkillsUSA uses to register, inform, and provide services to member organizations and individuals, the required data from participants often falls under the definition of “directory information” under 34 CFR § 99.3. This information can include, but is not limited to, a student’s name; address; telephone number; and email address. SkillsUSA does not request social security numbers. Schools and/or students have the option to enter school-provided student identification numbers. In many cases, under our agreements with member organizations, SkillsUSA is performing an institutional service or function that a member would otherwise assign to its own employees, under the direct control of the member organization and according to the criteria specified in the member’s annual FERPA notification. As such, SkillsUSA is acting as a school official and, therefore, is covered under the school official exemption under FERPA at 34 CFR § 99.31(a)(1).
While SkillsUSA requests information related to ethnicity, socio-economic and other demographics, this information is optional for students to share, and in addition to the questions being optional, most questions contain a “prefer to not respond” answer option. This information is in an aggregated format and does not identify any specific student and is used for analytical purposes only. This allows SkillsUSA to report on how students at a national or state level responded to the demographic and socio-economic questions. If, at a future point in time, SkillsUSA collects data containing PII other than directory information, we will follow all applicable regulations regarding the protection and disclosure of that data if the need arises.
If you wish to access, modify, or delete other personal information that you have provided to SkillsUSA, such as your address, please contact us at anyinfo@skillsusa.org for assistance.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. Please contact us if you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. Otherwise, SkillsUSA will download user data on a quarterly basis, retain that data for one year, and then dispose of the previous year’s data.
III. Use of Information
Generic information like names and email addresses are used for members’ personal accounts and to provide specific services. Such information will be used to issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments and send information about SkillsUSA and our services. Individuals may opt-out of mailings at any time if they do not wish to receive non-business critical information from us.
Demographic information is combined with monitoring trends in individuals registering and participating in SkillsUSA programs and is not tied to individual accounts. Data is shared only with operation-critical third-party vendors connected directly to the functionality of the online curricular resources and reporting. Data is not shared with other third-party vendors, and contact information is not provided to any commercial or non-commercial entities.
SkillsUSA takes appropriate steps to protect the security of all personal information that is collected and stored. Security policies, rules, and technical measures are implemented to protect the personal data from unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure; unauthorized modification; and unlawful destruction or accidental loss.
If SkillsUSA becomes aware of a systems security breach by an unauthorized party or that any user data was used for an unauthorized purpose, we will comply with relevant state and other data breach laws. We will notify users of any breach resulting in an unauthorized release of data electronically, at minimum, and without unreasonable delay so that you can take appropriate steps. The notification will include the date of the breach, the types of information that were subject to the breach, general description of what occurred and steps SkillsUSA is taking to address the breach.
All employees who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of all PII, have undergone background checks, and have received COPPA and FERPA training.
SkillsUSA does not share PII with any third-party organizations without prior written consent from its members. Even in cases where SkillsUSA is performing an institutional service or function that a member would otherwise assign to its own employees, under the direct control of the member organization and according to the criteria specified in the member’s annual FERPA notification, SkillsUSA will still follow all applicable FERPA rules regarding the use and protection against unauthorized disclosure of all PII involved.
Portions of the SkillsUSA LMS and the Website contain functions for collecting personal information, including names and email addresses, as well as an individual’s or account’s access history. SkillsUSA may also collect and track other personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information about you, such as your I.P. address, the type of browser you use, and the website you visited before visiting our website or SkillsUSA services.
If you are using the SkillsUSA LMS as an educational institution, student information may be visible during customer support and/or troubleshooting. Personally identifiable information such as Student
Name; Student Email Address; file names; creation dates of files; login dates and times; and third-party applications that students use could be viewed on our service by product support staff.
If you register to use the {SkillsUSA Service} or express interest in obtaining additional information, SkillsUSA requires you to provide your contact information, such as your name, school name, address, and email address. SkillsUSA may also ask for additional personal information, such as title, phone number, or other demographic or socio-economic information. You can opt-out of providing this additional information by not entering it when asked.
IV. Rights and Responsibilities
While SkillsUSA is not an educational institution subject to the requirements of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), except in cases where members outsource institutional services or functions to SkillsUSA, we are a national membership organization, with state and local chapters, that serves students attending institutions that are subject to FERPA, including high schools, colleges, middle schools, and other non-federal entities. All member organizations have the right to review student information provided to SkillsUSA and can request information be deleted or refuse to permit further collection or use of student data that has been provided. Members may make use of this right by contacting anyinfo@skillsusa.org and making such requests.
In light of this expansive membership, SkillsUSA is committed to helping member educational institutions stay in compliance with FERPA and its implementing regulations at 34 CFR Part 99. As noted above, the data that SkillsUSA collects is primarily directory information. Educational institutions that disclose directory information do not have to seek prior written consent from students or parents, as noted in 34 CFR § 99.31(a)(11). However, all educational institutions that might share this information with SkillsUSA must provide annual notification regarding this disclosure to parents and eligible students, including the right to opt-out of such disclosures. See 34 CFR § 99.37(a). Examples of such notifications can be found on the U.S. Department of Education’s Student Privacy Policy Office’s Website at: https://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/index.html.
Although SkillsUSA often qualifies for the school official exception under 34 CFR § 99.31(a)(1), it will still notify registering individuals when any non-directory information is required, and students or program directors may choose not to provide certain demographic information. Any non-directory information that is collected is used solely for tracking registration and performance trends and is not tied directly to individuals. Any non-directory information submitted by an individual is destroyed once annually or upon school administrator request.
Information provided to SkillsUSA may be used to transmit, distribute, modify, reproduce, display and store the student data solely for the purposes of providing the services as contemplated by the user’s agreement with SkillsUSA. Any internal use of information for maintaining, supporting, evaluating, improving, and developing our products, applications, and service, and for enforcing our rights under various agreements, will include all appropriate steps to protect all personally-identifiable information from unauthorized disclosure.
In the event that SkillsUSA is involved in a merger, reorganization, dissolution, sale of business or assets or similar event, information disclosed to or collected by SkillsUSA may be transferred to SkillsUSA’s’ successor, or to the purchaser of such assets, as applicable. You will be notified via email and a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. This policy may change from time to time, so please review it frequently for any updates or changes. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you via email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our website at least 30 days prior to the change becoming effective.
SkillsUSA conducts regular security reviews of all systems through which student data is collected, maintained and transmitted. Members may request the results of such audits by contacting anyinfo@skillsusa.org. Additionally, SkillsUSA ensures that all employees and staff that collect, handle, or transmit student data are trained on all FERPA-related requirements to ensure student data is protected.
V. Questions and Contact Information
SkillsUSA welcomes comments and questions on this policy. We are dedicated to protecting your personal information and will make every reasonable effort to keep that information secure. If you believe that SkillsUSA has not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact us electronically or via postal mail at the address provided below, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
If you have any questions, please contact us:
anyinfo@skillsusa.org
SkillsUSA
14001 SkillsUSA Way
Leesburg, VA 20176
703-777-8810
FAX: 703-777-8999
The information you provide to us will also be covered by this policy, and SkillsUSA will work to reply to your questions or comments within 30 days.
SkillsUSA.org
© 2020 SkillsUSA Inc.
14001 SkillsUSA Way • Leesburg, Virginia 20176-5494
703-777-8810 • FAX: 703-777-8999
•
Email us
SkillsUSA Inc. is a national nonprofit and tax-exempt student organization under the Internal Revenue Service Code, Section (501)(c)(3).Copyright and Trademark / Privacy Policy
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish. Cookie settingsACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
